How could I ever describe this feeling?
That exhilarating sense of power? That sensation that we were finally meeting our destiny.
We were an army of travellers, nothing could stop us now.
It was wonderful to be part of a flock, to have all eighty of us flying in the same direction, to feel we were part of something bigger, greater than ourselves.
We were following the lead of the more experienced travellers, themselves following the paths of our ancestors.
They took us along the Atlantic coast, a slightly longer route, but with more opportunities to rest and feed.
I never thought about questioning them. It was liberating to hand over control. They had been there before, we just had to follow.
I had a thought for the solo travellers, the scared little birds travelling alone under the cover of darkness. I pitied them.
We didn’t have to hide, our pride carried us forward. Together, we were invincible.
We watched human villages and roads beneath us. So small, so fragile.
We remembered the poachers with their rifles, the children trying to catch us with nets and slingshots.
Try to catch us now, we laughed.
We kept pointing excitedly at human constructions, strange things most of us had never seen before.
A highway. A wind turbine. A power plant.
We all cheered, when we passed them by.
And then, suddenly our leaders grew quiet.
I looked around, and noticed that all signs of human activity had vanished.
I could feel a wave of anxiety passing among the flock: we travelled in silence, our movements tense, our necks craned.
We knew that we were flying towards something terrible.
Something there were no words to describe.
And then, we saw it.
Ahead of us lay an area of unimaginable emptiness.
An immense stretch of land that humans had been too terrified to conquer.
The world’s greatest desert. The Sahara.